<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>gd1970-08-18.142416.aud.knudsen.gems.flac1648</identifier>
  <uploader>mvernon54@yahoo.com</uploader>
  <addeddate>2018-06-29 22:59:43</addeddate>
  <date>1970-08-18</date>
  <curation>[curator]validator@archive.org[/curator][date]20180629230205[/date][comment]checked for malware[/comment]</curation>
  <title>Grateful Dead Live at Fillmore West on 1970-08-18</title>
  <creator>Grateful Dead</creator>
  <mediatype>etree</mediatype>
  <collection>GratefulDead</collection>
  <collection>etree</collection>
  <type>sound</type>
  <description>Set 1&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
SET1 [49:18] [0:12 intro]; Truckin [5:44]; [1:20 turn up the monitors];&lt;br /&gt;
Dire Wolf [3:53]; [0:32]; Friend Of The Devil [3:31]; [0:23]; Dark Hollow&lt;br /&gt;
[3:05]; [0:12]; Ripple [4:15] ? Brokedown Palace [4:16]; [0:25] % Operator&lt;br /&gt;
[2:27]; [0:25]; Rosalie McFall [2:57]; [0:19]; New Speedway Boogie [9:22];&lt;br /&gt;
[0:53]; Cold Jordan [2:22] ? Swing Low Sweet Chariot [3:40]; [0:42] %&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Set 2&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
SET2 [20:39 +] [0:04 intro]; Six Days On The Road [3:56] % [0:10]; Watcha&lt;br /&gt;
Gonna Do [4:16]; [0:13] % Glendale Train [4:11]; [0:10] % [0:07 intro];&lt;br /&gt;
Brown-Eyed Handsome Man [3:23]; [0:08] % Fair Chance To Know [4:09]; [0:02]&lt;br /&gt;
%&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Set 3&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
[1:24:06 +] [0:04 intro]; Dancin In The Streets [14:08]; [0:25];&lt;br /&gt;
Next Time You See Me [3:03]; [0:17]; Mama Tried [2:38]; [0:11] % Cryptical&lt;br /&gt;
Envelopment [2:02] ? drums [4:00] ? The Other One [8:50] ? Cryptical&lt;br /&gt;
Envelopment [2:03] ? Sugar Magnolia [3:54]; [0:09] % Attics Of My Life&lt;br /&gt;
[6:45]; [0:33]; It's A Man's World [12:02]; [0:25]; drums [0:11 ? Not Fade&lt;br /&gt;
Away [10:20]; [0:21] % Casey Jones [4:58] ? Uncle John's Band [6:33]; [0:14]&lt;br /&gt;
%&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
SET 1 is acoustic Dead; this is the complete set.&lt;br /&gt;
Pigpen plays piano on Truckin, Ripple &amp; New Speedway. Jerry switches to&lt;br /&gt;
electric guitar on New Speedway. David Nelson plays mandolin on Rosalie&lt;br /&gt;
McFall, Cold Jordan &amp; Swing Low. Marmaduke adds bass vocals to Cold Jordan&lt;br /&gt;
and Swing Low. The introduction goes: "Good evening and welcome to the&lt;br /&gt;
Fillmore West. Tonight you're going to spend an evening with the Grateful&lt;br /&gt;
Dead." &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
  <year>1970</year>
  <subject>Audience;Jamie Waddell;GEMS;Jeff Knudsen;Tom Markson;Jason Chastain;John Wenzel</subject>
  <venue>Fillmore West</venue>
  <coverage>San Francisco, CA</coverage>
  <source>&lt;b&gt;flac16/48kHz&lt;/b&gt;; Unknown Audience Cassette &gt; FLAC</source>
  <taper>From the Collection of Jeff Knudsen</taper>
  <transferer>Jason Chastain and Jamie Waddell and John Wenzel and Tom Markson</transferer>
  <runtime>130:58.011</runtime>
  <md5s>ef7b6d80ae7a159d363b3c1d45897631 *01 Truckin'.flac a241b17e1c01cc1c0644b6bbaa709911 *02 Dire Wolf.flac 9480d56301961655fc29f93586936a41 *03 Friend of the Devil.flac 3e83ac1902664493323fee756d43c84c *04 Dark Hollow.flac fef59ba6194b6bc933b31be30439cbc0 *05 Ripple.flac d1826e1a3b6ba3b4390a9135ac947157 *06 Brokedown Palace.flac 36315e8a28d9301760abda413bd4af04 *07 Operator.flac d142efc12d24172df592030cc0de7c3d *08 Rosalie McFall.flac 33bd151a21d47fd6e8ca8262ca0b51f9 *09 New Speedway Boogie.flac 6e4f7d8f1d54a3bf46571fe165fdb37c *10 Cold Jordan.flac c3ffeb5963f477b3fe9cd694f2ca6d1f *11 Swing Low Sweet Chariot.flac a7dee95135747aa806b26f41ebd41231 *12 Dancin' in the Streets.flac 66c9f1205cfadc5ae3ce1b3f845108be *13 Next Time you see me.flac 1f115a3363de3f7da8ac9fc57e317d0f *14 Mama Tried.flac c0af966a2c07bae3b34ac641457056ed *15 Cryptical Envelopment.flac 1a18edb9fe8c64679851379729b63535 *16 Drums.flac e972713cf43e98932281aebc66d7e5e2 *17 Other One.flac 3340ca8fe70f676c3cba3c2204af5628 *18 Cryptical Envelopment.flac ac347c9abe38da21db70b95bfcc22f15 *19 Sugar Magnolia.flac 5bee8e80189480cc3ae397512d65a05b *20 Attics of My Life.flac 72224ad5871f285d71730286e7f1cb5f *21 Man's World.flac b5e2673f792aca1ef036ab5087e9175d *22 Not Fade Away.flac 5eea59a635a9cac44f1d8aa60a18ea5b *23 Casey Jones.flac a6b90a4e7a4b356ed9a6437091b86082 *24 Uncle John's Band.flac</md5s>
  <notes>* - First recorded performances

** - with John "Marmaduke" Dawson and David Nelson

Source - We suspect that this audience recording was made by the same
unknown taper as the shnid 1346, circulated in August of 2000. Gene
Taback's recorder was taken away on this evening, so it is not his,
though he managed a more stealth taping of 8/19 with success. In 2018 an
attempt was made to speed correct 1346 and digitally process, resulting
in shnid 141071, received with mixed results at best. Because of the
inherent issues in the original shnid and the attempted fix, we chose to
transfer Jeff's copies of the audience tapes and were pleased with the
sound. Seemingly one generation closer to the master, but unlabeled as
usual for tapes of that era. The speed is right and the channel placement
is correct. 

In the Deadhead's Taping Compendium, Harvey Lubar writes:

"This show, as well as that on the night following, first appeared in tape
circulation in 1974, when the original recordist contacted my partner
for a trade. These shows catch the Dead as they were introducing the
music that would later appear on American Beauty. We took the original
cassette masters from both shows and transferred them to reels. Then,
in 1990, I transferred my reels to PGM/Beta. The taper noted that it
was Pigpen who played a stand-up piano throughout the acoustic set."

Judging from the previous shnid and Harvey's comments, we suspect a reel
and possibily beta is in the lineage.  The guess is Cass &gt; Reel &gt; Beta &gt;
Jeff's Cass. There is tape hiss, but the hiss really becomes listenable
quickly, and allows the nuances of the music to remain. No reduction
was employed digitally.


Jeff Knudsen has been an avid Jerry Garcia, Grateful Dead and San
Francisco Sound music fan for over 40 years. From a letter to Dead Relix
Magazine asking for help cultivating a tape collection, Jeff developed
a relationship with Dick Latvala and many other tapers, building an
enormous music collection. He also taped many Jerry Garcia shows at
venerable institutions like the various Keystones. Jeff loved to share
tapes in a twinkle of an eye. He was a key player in leaking the Betty
Boards back in the day. A few years ago, he decided he should pass his
collection on to someone who could properly archive and transfer. After
a few years of offering it publicly, there were no takers. In 2018,
Arizona LL members Jamie and Tom felt the Knudsen collection was too
valuable to let go. After a flight so bumpy that we almost cried, and
a great visit, albeit too short, with Jeff... 1200 lbs of tapes, gear
and cds were lovingly packed at his Florida homestead. The next era of
his beloved collection is summer camp for the tapes in the desert... an
ongoing process of cataloging and transferring the contents to share. Born
from decades of Jeff's passion for live music collecting and the archival
efforts of many, it's an honor and a privilege to share the Knudsen
Tapes with you. 



Enjoy!  



originally shared at www.shnflac.net</notes>
  <publicdate>2018-06-30 23:04:32</publicdate>
  <backup_location>ia906707_32</backup_location>
</metadata>
